GuilhermeDeMaio

Software Developer

contact

R. Ministro Gastão Mesquita, 257 05012-010 São Paulo Brasil

+55 11 9 8393 2639 • guilherme_nirev guilherme@nirev.org http://nirev.org

○/nirev **y**/nirev

in/nirev

languages

native portuguese fluent english basic french

programming

Elixir, Java, Ruby, Javascript, C, Python, HTML, css, bash, Kafka, Spark, docker, monitoring tools

interests

distributed systems, making a better world, data structures, music, martial arts, science fiction books

about me

I've been developing software for 10 years, from web apps to embedded media applications. During this time I've come to believe that: - Empathy first, always - Trust is key - Less is more

On the tech side of things, I'm more of a backend/operations type, but I do dabble a bit on the frontend. I enjoy taking part and ownership of where and how applications are deployed and monitored.

I take pride in being part of team. I enjoy giving talks and getting to know people at conferences. I've been a team lead before, and I dislike the term "soft skills". Once you're in a position as such, those so called "soft" skills are exactly what is most important.

recent experience

September 2015 - *

Senior Software Engineer at XERPA

São Paulo - Brazil

I joined the company as their first employee to help build the SaaS platform tackling HR bureaucracy in Brazil. We started from day-0 with Elixir and Phoenix on the backend, with the frontend initially in simple html/css/jquery. We eventually migrated the frontend to Clojure-Script using a GraphQL API.

Among things I took part are:

- Bootstrapped the platform using Elixir, Phoenix and PostgreSQL
- Managing infrastructure with Terraform and Ansible
- Built libraries for:
- Authentication and Authorization
- Indexing things to ElasticSearch, as well as defining mappings
- Resizing and manipulating images
- Integrating with payment gateways
- Defining and prioritizing features together with product and business/sales teams. I also did visit "beta" clients in the beginning to get a better understanding of the problems we needed to solve.
- Collaborating heavily with Customer Success team to help streamline client usage after signup, focusing on quickly solving bugs and creating stories to improve the user experience
- Using OCR to identify unique numbers in PDFs, built a document distribution feature which greatly improved sales and customer satisfaction.

November 2012 – September 2015

Team Lead (Search and Analytics) at Elo7

São Paulo - Brazil

A marketplace with high traffic and transaction volume. The stack was based on Java, Ruby and Scala on AWS infrastructure. A fast paced environment, with agile practices, and focusing on delivering fast with quality. We measured and logged using StatsD, Graphite, and NewRelic, and deployed constantly. I was leading the Search and Analytics Team: a small team using Solr, Kafka and Spark to improve search and real time reports, and responsible for its infrastructure and pipeline tools.

past experiences details available upon request

04/2012to10/2012 - Intern at INRIA Paris-RoquencourtParis - France03/2011to09/2012 - Undergrad Researcher at USP - CHOReOS projectSão Paulo - Brazil08/2010to02/2011 - Software Developer (C/C++) at RR SistemaVitória/ES - Brazil01/2009to12/2010 - Undergrad Intern at Multimedia and Network Research LabVitória/ES - Brazil08/2008to12/2008 - Undergrad Intern at LASSYUniversity of Luxembourg - LU03/2007to12/2007 - Undergrad Intern at NINFA laboratoryVitória/ES - Brazil09/2006to03/2007 - PHP Developer at Lettera SoluçõesVitória/ES - Brazil

education

2011–2014 Master in Computer Science University of São Paulo - Brazil
2005–2010 B.Sc. in Computer Science Federal University of Espírito Santo - Brazil